Guide to the James Deitrick Papers, 1900-1918
Department of Special Collections
- 1916, January - December (Folder 9)
  - 47. July & August.Norwegian Whaling Co., Stock list.
  - 48. Aug. 11.Dunham, Carrigan & Hayden Co. to Chinese-American Plantation Co., Bill.
  - 49. Aug. 31.Dunham, Carrigan & Hayden Co. to J.D., Bill.
  - 50. Sept. 19.[J.D.] to J. G. Hammond. Mexico, coquito nut kernels., T.L.
  - 51. Oct. 6,Arnold Neble to J.D., Tel.
  - 52. Oct. 16.D. Y. Geddes to J.D. Pottery works., T.L.S.
  - 53. Oct. 17.J.D. to Sloane Gordon., Tel.
  - 54. Oct. 17.Sloane Gordon to J.D., Tel.
  - 55. Oct. 17.A. L. Rohrer to [J.D.], T.L.S.
  - 56. Oct. 23.[J.D.] to Vladimir Generosoff. Mexican sisal., T.L.
  - 57. Oct. 23.Ernest Telkes to Magda Telkes von Kelenfold. Prison camp., A.pc.S.
  - 58. Oct. 24.[J.D.] to Mr. Denisoff. Mexican sisal., T.L.
  - 59. Oct. 27.Ernest Telkes to J.D., A.pc.S.
  - 60. Oct. 28.Dunham, Carrigan & Hayden Co. to Chinese-American Plantation Co., Bill.
  - 61. Oct. 30.[J.D.] to Lin Sun. Airplanes, T.L. (frag.)
  - 62. Oct. 30.Sloane Gordon to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 63. Nov. 7.[J.D.] to Sloane Gordon. Mexico shipping and mining., T.L. (frag.)
  - 64. Nov. 13.George T. Webb to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 65. Nov. 15.[J.D.] to Wu T'ing-fang. Railroad, Canton to Yunnan-fu., A.L.
  - 66-67. Nov. 16.Sloane Gordon to J.D., 2 T.L.S.
  - 68. Nov. 22.Sloane Gordon to J.D. China, Lower California, manganese., T.L.S.
  - 69. 1916, Nov. 23.Christofferson Aircraft Mfg. Co. to Sam Mustain., Receipt.
  - 70. Dec. 5.Sloane Gordon to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 71. Dec. [11 or 16?][J.D.] to Sloane Gordon. Mexico, politics, manganese, clays, Arizona mining, General episode., A.L.
  - 72. Dec. 21.Wu T'ing-fang (by sec.) to J.D. & cvr., T.L.
  - 73. Dec. 29.[Alaska Packers Assn.] to Estaban Cantu with descriptions of 2 steamers., T.L.
  - 74. 1916.Sailing schedule. Norwegian America Line.
  - 75. 1916.The Russell & Co., Price list.
- 1917 (Folder 10)
  - 1. Jan. 17.[J.D.] to Esteban Cantu. Mexico, steamships, airplanes, railroad., T.L.
  - 2. Feb. 11.Sam J. Mustain to Nom Lui (Chinese Nationalist League of America). Pilot, appeal for pay & expenses., T.L.S.
  - 3. Feb. 18.[S. J. Lesh] to J.D. Electrical detection of ore bodies., A.L.S.
  - 4. Feb. 22.[J.D.] to Tong Sui Nune. Mustain., T.L.
  - 5. Mar. 5.F. H. G[ould] to William Kettner., T.L.
  - 6. Mar. 29.Sloane Gordon to J.D. Lower Calif., T.L.S.
  - 7-8. Apr. 9.[J.D.] to Sloane Gordon. Mexico, coquito nut kernels, mines, shipping, cotton & sugar cane lands, railroad plans, iron., 2 T.L. (1 frag.)
  - 9. Apr. 12.Ernest Telkes to J.D., A.pc.S.
  - 10. May 10.[J.D.] to John A. McCarthy & Edward Mosehauer. Failure in Russia & China, Mexico, mining., T.L.
  - 11. May 14.Nathan Hale Volunteers (Frederic Sumner Hughes) to [J.D.] re: I.D. cards & emblems. With blank Suspect Report, 2 ptd. announcements., T.L.S.
  - 12. May 16.R. M. Ritter to J.D. Dr. Hugo Schweitzer., T.L.S.
  - 13. May 18.Carlos [Ystas y C.] to J.D. Rifle, Cantu, Col. Macias, Pres. Carranzo., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1917, May 24.Nathan Hale Vols. (F. S. Hughes) to J.D. with 2 membership application blanks., T.N.S.
  - 15. May 28.[J.D.] to Esteban Cantu. Rifle, Col. Macias, Mexicali-San Felipe RR., T.L.
  - 16. May.3 blank authorizations to Crocker National Bank.
  - 17. [1917, May?]George O. Squire to J.D., A.L. (copy)
  - 18. June 6.[J.D.] to Y. Nagashima of Mitsui & Co. Proposed cotton plantation., T.L.
  - 19. June 25.Barton W. Evermann to Sec. San Francisco Chamber of Commerce. Whale meat as food., T.L.
  - 20. June 26.H. Lawton to J.D. Mexican agricultura land., T.L.S.
  - 21. Jul. 14.[J.D.] to Sloane Gordon. Mexico, manganese., A.L.
  - 22. Jul. 18.Sloane Gordon to J.D. Copper property Arizona, Mexico., T.L.S.
  - 23. Jul. 19.J. [E.] Kiler to J.D., A.L.S.
  - 24. Aug. 2.Eduardo C. Garcia to R. D. Micotti. Mexico, fertilizer plant., T.L.S.
  - 25. Aug. 3.Ralph [E.] Young to J.D. Mexico, bandit Espinoza., T.L.S.
  - 26. Aug. 16.H. Lawton to J.D. Southern Pacific RR, Mexico, draft., T.L.S.
  - 27. Aug. 21.[J.D.] to Intelligence Officer, Western Division, U. S. Army. Draft dodgers & deserters in Mexico, anti-American signs, German business houses and influence, train robbery, Francisco Espinosa & Ernest Radke., T.L.
  - 28. Aug. 25.C. D. Smead to J.D. Photo of McPherson., T.L.S.
  - 29. Aug. 29.L. J. Williams of Philippine Scouts to J.D. Visit to Angel Island., T.L.S.
  - 30. Aug. 30.Homer Wilson to J.D.M. Manganese., Tel.
  - 31. Aug. 31.Telfair Creighton to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 32. [Sept. 1?]J.D. to Homer Wilson., Tel.
  - 33. [Sept. 1?]Homer Wilson to J.D., Tel.
  - 34. 1917, Sept. 2.W. A. Mundell to J.D. Requests interview re J.D.'s possible involvement in Hindu conspirators case., T.L.S.
  - 35. Sept. 5.Delos C. Emmons to J.D. Henley., T. Memo S.
  - 36. Oct. 1.Second Liberty Loan of 1917 to [J.D.], T.L. (form)
  - 37-41. Oct. 4.Samuel J. Mustain to Chinese Nationalis League of America; statement of employment; amount due; - J.D., 2 A.N.S. T.L.S.
  - 42. Oct. 9.Robert S. Norman to J.D. Mustain., T.L.S.
  - 43. Oct. 15.J.D. to [Samuel J. Mustain?], A.L.S.
  - 44-45. Oct. 18.Samuel J. Mustain to F. H. Gould with Power of Attorney., T.L.S.
  - 46. Oct. 20.F. H. Gould to Lin Sun et al., T.L.
  - 47. Nov. 16.Presidential Proclamation - Alien Enemies., Ptd. copy.
  - 48. Nov. 28.Presidential Proclamation - Exports., Typed copy.
  - 49. Nov. 28.Presidential Proclamation - Imports., Typed copy.
  - 50. Dec. 8.Certificate of J.D. deposition Oct. 23, 1917., Copy.
    - a. Post Wheeler cert. of Shinjiro Hashimoto deposition.
    - b. Oct. 23.Shinjiro Hashimoto deposition.
    - c. Oct. 23.J. W. Ballantine cert. of translation.
    - d-f. Oct. 20-22.certs of contracts.
  - 51-52. Dec. 11.Ryozo Hashimoto to J.D. Steel plates for war ships., A.L.S.
  - 53. [1917].Nathan Hale Vols. to [J.D.] and 2 suspect report forms. s. Rufus W. Putnam, U.S.A. Intelligence Officer., T.L.S. (form)
  - 54. [1918, May 19?]Unknown (Junzaburo) to J.D., Tel. in code.
- UNDATED MATERIAL AND FRAGMENTS (Folder 11)
  - Jan. 24.[W.] P. Richardson to J.D.; n.d.2nd page of T.L. J.D. to Unknown re: Russian business plans, from Petrograd; n.d.2nd page describes Hungarian childhood, Magyars, typed; n.d.a holograph postscript re: contracts sent to Hammond; Misc. memos and notes mostly re: Russian business plans; G. T. Webb report on farming North Dakota; resolution re: potash shipments; clays for pottery etc.; report (frag.) on agricultural land in Sinaloa, Mexico, also memo; description of steamer Jennie; Chinese-American Syndicate confidential memo.
- MISCELLANEOUS (Folder 12)
  Notes, sketches, autographs, bills, telegrams, printed material, callingcards.
- MAPS (Folder 13)
  - 1. Asia ca. 1915.Ptd. with pencil additions.
  - 2. Russian Volunteer Fleet Sailing Routes ca. 1915.Ptd., pencil & ink notations. Vladivostok & Lena River.
  - 3. Russian Empire ca. 1915.Printed in Russian
  - 4. Russian Empire ca. 1910.Partial showing Turkestan area, Omsk south to Lake Balkhash (now Kazakh S.S.R.) in Russian.
  - 5. Russian Empire 1910.Blowup of #4. East of Lake Balkhash along Ili River between Ili and Kuldja in China or Mongolia. Printed in Russian
  - 6. Russian Empire 1910.Holograph tracing of #5 showing proposed canal routes, mining, grazing and swamp areas.
  - 7. Russian Empire ca. 1915.Hand executed map showing the junctions of the Narym and Bukhtarma Rivers with the Irtysh River and the towns of Zyryanovsk and Aleksandrovskaja (now [UNK]) on the [Berezovka] River.
- Photographs (Folder 14)
  - 1) 9 prints from the air show in Kobe, Japan.
    See also nitrate negative file for 15 negatives, 9 of which have prints with them.
  - 2) 7 8x10 prints of [UNK] [California?]
inserts to Index
Additional Information
PARTIAL INDEX OF CORRESPONDENTS AND SUBJECTS
(Numbers refer to folders)
Agriculture, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 10, 11.
Airplanes, 9, 10, 14,
Alaska, 2, 4.
Albion, Calif., 2.
Arizona, 9, 10.
Baja California, 9, 10.
Barbour, William, 1.
Beal, C. N., 5, 9.
Best, C. L., Gas Traction Company, 2, 3, 6, 7, 9.
Boisse, Jean, 1.
Boone Trail, 9.
Burke, John, 3.
California, 2, 5.
Cantu, Esteban, 9, 10.
Carleton, Mark Alfred, 3.
Chamberlain, George Earle, 3, 8.
Chilton, William Edwin, 1.
China, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 8, 9, 10, 13.
Chinese-American Plantation Company, 8, 9, 11.
Chinese Nationalist League of America, 9, 10.
Clay, 9, 11.
Colt's Patent Fire Arms Manufacturing Company, 5, 6, 9.
Cotton, 10.
Emerson-Brantingham Implement Company, 3, 5.
Ermolof, Alexis Sergius, 4
Evermann, Barton Warren, 10.
INDEX - 2
Goeke, John Henry, 1, 3.
Gordon, Sloane, 9, 10.
Gould, Frank Horace, 10.
Hughes, Frederic Sumner, 10.
Hughitt, Marvin, 9.
Januszewski, Z., 8.
Japan, 2, 5.
Lansing, Robert, 9.
Lawton, H., 10.
Manganese, 9, 10.
Marye, George Thomas, 7, 8.
Mexican sisal, 9.
Mexico, 9, 10, 11.
Mongolia, 1, 4, 13.
Murphy, J. S., 3.
Mustain, Samuel J., 10.
Nathan Hale Volunteers, 10.
Natomas Consolidated of California, 2.
Netherlands Farms Company, 2.
Nicaragua, 1, 2.
Nicaragua Timber and Fruit Lands Company, 1.
North Dakota, agriculture, 3, 11.
O'Gorman, James A., 1, 2.
Petrograd, Russia, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
Polkhovski, Joseph, 5, 8.
Potash, 9, 11.
INDEX - 3
Railroads, 2, 4, 5, 7, 9, 10, 11.
Rohrer, A. L., 9.
Ropp, Baron E., 6.
Russell and Company, The, 7, 8, 9.
Russian Empire, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 10, 11, 13.
Russian Land Reclamation Company Ltd., 6.
Shuster, William Morgan, 8.
Simon, Georges, 1.
Skorniakoff, Eugene E., 5.
Smedberg, C. Renwick, 9.
Spurgeon, John J., 9.
Stevens, John Franklin, 2.
Storey, William Benson, 2.
Stuart, Henry Clifford, 2, 3, 9.
Sugar beet seeds, 8, 9.
Sun, Yat-sen, 2, 3, 4.
Telkes family, 2, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10.
Telkes de Kelenfold, Ernest, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10.
Timber, 2, 5.
Townsend, Charles Orrin, 8, 9.
Trans-Siberian Railway, 4, 7, 11.
Tumulty, Joseph Patrick, 8.
Turkestan, 4, 13
East, 8, 13.
Walsh, Thomas James, 2.
War armaments and equipment, 5, 6, 7, 9, 10.
Webb, George T., 3, 9, 11.
Wellman, Peck, and Company, 5.
INDEX - 4
Whales and whaling, 9, 10.
White, Frederick W., 9.
Winslow, Edward Delbert, 4.
Wright, George Frederick, 2.
Wu, T'ing-fang, 9.
PARTIAL INDEX OF CORRESPONDENTS & SUBJECTS
(Numbers refer to folders)
name or subject folder number
Agmenlture 1-6, 9, 10, 11
Alrpleures 9, 10
Alaska 2, 4,
Albion, Calif 2
Baja Califomica 9, 10
Beal, C. N. 5, 9
Best, C. L., Gas [UNK] Company 2, 3 6, 7, 9
Boisse, Jean 1
Burke, John (1) 1859 - 1937 3
Canter, Esteban 9, 10
Calif General, Gov. of Lower 2, 5
Carleton, Mark. Alfred 1866 - 1925 (1) Am. plant pathologist 3
Chamberlain, George Earle 1854 - 1928 Am. politician 3, 8
Chilton, William Edwin (1) 1858 - 1939 senator 1
China - business in, agriculture, railroads, politics 1-4, 5, 8-10, 13 (map)
Chinese - American Plantation Co. 8, 9, 11
Chinese Nationalist League of America 9, 10
Clay 9, 11
Coefs' Patent Fire Arms Manufacturing Company 5, 6 9
Cotton 10
Emerson - Brantingham Implement Company 3, 5
Ermolof, Alexis Sergius 4
Evermann, Barton Warren 1853 - 1932 naturalist (1) 10
Goeke, John Henry 1869 - 1930 lawyer 1, 3
Gordon, Sloane 9, 10
Gould, Frank Horace-lawyer 1856 - 1918 (1) 10
Guns 5-7, 9
Januszewski, Z. 8
Japan 2, 5
Lansing, Robert (1) 1864 - 1928 Am. lawyer & statesman 9
Lawton, H. 10
Manganese 9, 10
Marye, George Thomas 1849 - 1933 ambassador 7, 8
Mexican sisal 9,
Mexico 9, 10, 11
Mongolia 1, 4, 13 (map)
Murphy, J. S. 3
Mustain, Samuel J. 10
Nathan Hale Volunteers 10
Natomas Consolidated of California 2
Netherlands Farms Company 2
Nicaragua 1, 2
Nicaragua Timber & Fruit Lands Co. 1
North Dakota Agriculture 3, 11
O'Gorman, James A. 1, 2
Petrograol, Russia 3-8
Polkhovski, Joseph 5, 8
Potash 9, 11
Railroads 2, 4, 5, 7, 9, 10, 11
Rohter, A. L. 9
Ropp. Baren E. 6
Russell & Co., The (E. C. Merwin) 7, 8, 9
Russian Empire 1, 2-7, 10, 11, 13 (maps)
Russian Land Reclamation Co. Ltd. 6
Shuster, William Morgan 1877 - (1) Am. lawyer, financier & publish 8
[UNK], George 1
Skorniakoff Engene E. 6
Smedberg, C. Renwick 9
Storey, William Benson 1857-1940 [UNK] official 2
[UNK], Henry Clifford 2, 3, 9
Sugar beet seeds 8, 9
Sun Yat-sen ([UNK], Wen & Chung [UNK] Shan) 1866-1925 Chinese statesman & revolutionary leader 2, 3, 4
Telkes family 2, 4-10
Telkes de Kelenfold, Béla 2
Telkes de Kelenfold, Ernest [UNK]-10
Tunber 2, 5
Townsend, Charles [UNK] 1863 - 1937 pathologist 8, 9
Trans-Siberian Railroad 4, 7, 11
Tumulty, Joseph [UNK] (1) 1879- Am. lawyer, pvt. see to Woodrow Wilson 8
Turkestan 4, 13(map)
Turkestan, East 8, 13 (map)
Walsh, Thomas James (1) 1759-1933 Am. lawyer & legislator 2
Webb, George T. 3, 9, 11
Wellman, Peek & Co. 5
Whales & Whaling 9, 10
White, Frederick W. (1) 1863 - 1937 chem. mfr. 9
Winslow, Edward Delbert (1) 1858 - 1941 [UNK] gen. 4
Wright, George Frederick 1838 - 1921 [UNK] 2
Wu T'ing - fang (1) 1842 - 1922 Chinese diplomat 9
Arizona 9, 10
Barbour, William d. 1917 (1) 1
Boone [UNK] 9
Hughitt, Marvin 1837 - 1928 [UNK] official (1) 9
Hughes, Frederic Sumner (1) 10
Hindu [UNK] case (1) 10
Stevens, John Franklin (1) 1870 - 1933 consulting [UNK] 2
Spurgeon, John J. (1) 9
Wilson, Homer 10
Armaments 5-7, 9
Ships 7, 10